A Guide to the James Remly Papers, 1832-1853
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
James Remly Papers, 1832-1853.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 76.4
13 items.
James Remly, b. 1815?
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1976.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm (M-1560)
Biographical/Historical Information
James Remly (b. ca. 1815), son of Elias Remly of Lewisburg, Va. Attended the College of William and Mary during the 1834-1835 session, and boarded with the Rev. Scervant Jones of Williamsburg (1785-1854). Remly later became an itinerant Baptist preacher in Greenbrier County, Va.
Scope and Content Information
The papers include a teaching contract for Pocahontas County, Va., 1832, and a letter, 1835, by the Rev. Scervant Jones sanctioning Remly's preaching ability. The remaining items appear to relate to Remly's ordination, 1837, his certification to perform marriages, 1840, quarterly reports on his missionary activities, 1839-1841, as well as notes for sermons, records of miles traveled on his circuit, baptisms, and miscellaneous letters. Names in the collection include Joseph Alderson, Lewis Allen Alderson, Rev. Joseph Brown, Brother Dempsey, Brother Feller, Brother Harris, D. G. Margrave, Brother William Sands, John Spotts, and Edwin W. Woodson.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Persons:
Alderson, Joseph.; Alderson, Lewis Allen.; Brown, Joseph.; Dempsey, Mr.; Feller, Mr.; Harris, Mr.; Jones, Scervant, 1785-1854.; Margrave, D. G.; Remly, James, b. 1815.; Sands, William.; Spotts, John.
Subjects:
Clergy--Virginia-- History-- 19th century.; Clergy--West Virginia--Greenbrier County--History--19th century.; Education--Virginia-- Pocahontas County-- History--19th century.; Baptists--Virginia--History--19th century.
Corporate Names:
Greenbrier Baptist Association.
Contents List
- Teaching contract for J. Remly in Huntersville, Pocohontas County, Virginia, 23 August 1832.
- Williamsburg, S. Jones' certification of J. Remly's preaching ability, 18 October 1835.
- J. Remly's letter of ordination from Greenbriar Association, 11 September 1837.
- J. Remly, Howard's Creek, to W. Sands, 30 September 1839.
- J. Remly, Howard's Creek, to W. Sands, 25 November 1839.
- J. Remly to W. Sands, 12 March 1840.
- J. Remly, Howard's Creek, to W. Sands, 7 May 1840.
- J. Remly to W. Sands, 22 September 1840.
- Remly's certification to perform Baptist marriages, 24 November 1840.
- J. Remly to W. Sands, 2 December 1840.
- J. Remly, Howard's Creek, to W. Sands, 4 March 1841.
- J. Remly, Lewisburg, to J. Brown, 15 February 1842.
- J. Remly's notes for lecture to Greenbriar Agricultural Society, 9 July 1853.